Paing Soe Thu (Koppai)

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

Email | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio | +959796679793

SUMMARY

A conscientious web developer experienced in creating aesthetic web designs using React & Redux. Built 10+ projects in just three months. Achieved outstanding score (61/64) in the first module's final assessment at Microverse. I am committed to maintaining a strong and positive mindset through regular workouts and meditation.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Self-Motivator

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Front-End Web Developer

Remote

April 2023 - Present

<u>Dota2 Heros</u> — A responsive web application that allows users to learn about Dota2 heroes. Users can search for heroes and learn about their abilities and stats. This project was built with React.js and Redux.

<u>SiriBox</u> — A dynamic and responsive website that showcases a collection of movies and TV shows. Users can filter shows according to genres and interact by liking and commenting on their favorite shows on the website. Built with: JavaScript, Webpack, Bootstrap, HTML

<u>Leaderboard</u> — This is a responsive app that you can use to input your scores. It displays all of the user inputs from anywhere from the best score to the worst score.

MICROVERSE Remote
Mentor (Volunteer) May 2023 - Present

- Providing mentorship to junior web developers, offering technical guidance and support through code reviews.
- Offering valuable insights and practical guidance on sustaining motivation for long-term success in the program, as well as strategies for maximizing learning from coding partners.
- Suggesting enhancements to code organization, resulting in improved code quality and enhanced performance.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE April 2023 – Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spending 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and front-end development while simultaneously developing projects with JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developing skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

MYANMAR MARITIME UNIVERSITY

September 2016 - March 2023

B.E, Naval Architecture, and Ocean Engineering

- Developed and presented projects focused on the structural analysis of ships.
- Learned Engineering Mathematics, Stability, Structures, Mechanics of Materials, Vibration, and Steel Designs.
- Graduated as one of the top two students in our major.